## JEFFREY REEVE

DATA SCIENTIST

#### **ABOUT**

I'm a seasoned professional with an extensive background in Finance and Healthcare, including 6 years in analytical roles and 2 years in data roles. I'm passionate about Data Science and I love telling data stories! My work defines data, enhances efficiency, clarifies communication, and increases insight.

## QUALIFICATIONS

- Skill sets in Python, R, PostgreSQL, Tableau, and Machine Learning
- Understanding of ETL, data cleaning, and EDA
- Experience creating dashboards and data stories using multiple data visualization technologies
- Experience analyzing data and delivering insights using Python and R on multiple projects
- Published analyst & writer whose work was distributed to an audience of more than 2.5 million
- Background communicating technical, complex material to a non-technical, layperson audience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### CUSTOM SOFTWARE ENGINEERING ANALYST

Accenture Federal Services, Nashville, TN / November 2022 - Present

- Researched and analyzed the blockchain/crypto space in R and Python, providing insights for a government agency
- Analyzed and visualized workforce analytics in R and Tableau, providing insights for a government agency

#### **DATA SCIENCE APPRENTICE**

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN / September 2022 - Present

- Currently enrolled in an intensive program covering Python,
  R, SQL, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning
- Used R to create an R Shiny application examining the relationship between unemployment & inflation over time

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ANALYST

Accenture, Nashville, TN / August 2021 – October 2022

• Gathered, analyzed, and visualized data, providing insights for consumer goods & payment services companies

#### **DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE**

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN / January 2021 – April 2021

- Completed intensive program covering 5 major technologies
- Used Tableau to create a data story capstone project: An Examination of the Cost of COVID-19 in the United States

i jeffrey.m.reeve@gmail.com

 i jeffrey.m.reeve@gmail.com

720 270-1423 www.linkedin.com/in/jeffreyreeve

#### **EDUCATION**

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Nashville, TN

Data Science Program Student

## NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Nashville, TN

Data Analytics Program Graduate

### UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN -LA CROSSE

La Crosse, WI

Bachelor of Science (BS), Finance

#### **SKILLS**

Data Science

**Data Analytics** 

**Data Visualization** 

Data Journalism

Python

R

SQL

Tableau

Power BI

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Statistical Analysis

Research

**Analysis** 

Writing

Agile

GitHub

#### **MARKET ANALYST**

Charles Schwab, Denver, CO / October 1999 – January 2004

• Researched, analyzed, wrote, edited, distributed & broadcast Daily Market Updates to an audience of 2.5+ million people

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified: Power BI Data Analyst Associate